so one very popular approach would be to
combine the magnetic disks with flash
the magnetic disk is very cheap per
gigabyte compared to flash we know how
to build huge capacity magnetic disks in
a relatively small package but it's very
power hungry
it spins
and consumes power even when not
accessing data
and it's very slow because it has to
mechanically move things around in order
to access data
and another disadvantage of magnetic
disks is that they are sensitive to
impact like if they fall down and hit
the ground while they are spinning
because their heads are then likely to
scratch the surface of the disk and
permanently damage the whole track
possibly and maybe the head itself
flash on the other hand is fast power
efficient and has no moving parts so if
it falls down it might get damaged but
it's very unlikely
so the idea is to have both of them and
use the flash effectively as a cache for
the disk
that way most of the data
is on the disk but the data we are
frequently accessing
is on the flash where it's fast
it can be accessed without moving parts
and it can be accessed very efficiently
now of course the disk would still be
spinning
if we occasionally access it but if we
have enough flash to access data in it
for even
minutes at a time we can actually power
down the disk and spin it down and only
really access it once we have a flash
miss
and because both of these
can keep their data without power
if we turn off power suddenly
the data in the flash
will still survive
and so will the data on the disk
unlike for example if we use a magnetic
disk with the dram cache to keep the
most recently accessed data